BENJAMIN CAMPBELL

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

0421 364 254

bccbass@gmail.com

benjamincampbell.dev

GitHub

in LinkedIn

Caringbah, NSW 2229

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript (ES6+) | Python | Node.js | Express | Flask | React | RESTful API | SQL-PostGreSQL | NoSQL-MongoDB | HTML | CSS | Git/GitHub | Agile

SOFT SKILLS

Communication | Teamwork | Adaptable | Strong Work Ethic | Project Oriented | Interpersonal Skills | Patient | Systems Thinker | Growth Mindset

EDUCATION

Diploma of IT

Coder Academy

2023

Bachelor of Music, Jazz Studies

University of Southern California

1999-2003

INTERESTS

 Analog synthesizers: mainly collecting analog synthesizers from the 1970's and 1980's and learning subtractive and FM synthesis.

- Building and repairing analog guitar pedals.
- All things espresso: roasting, repairing and modding machines and imbibing.

PROFILE

Software engineer with a team focused and project oriented mindset. Strong functional programming approach with a passion for solving problems. A clear communicator possessing a positive and supportive attitude. Experienced in full stack web development, creating elegant and accessible code and mapping traditional music creation to modern technological paradigms.

KEY PROJECTS

Yahtzee!

- Implemented Python to create a terminal based version of the classic game Yahtzee!
- Utilized a functional programming approach to create a DRY code base to facilitate gameplay.
- Incorporated full unit testing and error handling to create a robust user experience.

Feature Website

- Personal website created to present composition, production and performance, generating professional interest and interactions.
- Utilized JavaScript, CSS and HTML to create effective UX/UI.

Personnel API

- RESTful API to catalog session musicians contributions to recordings.
- Flask Web Server connected to PostgreSQL database.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Musician/Bassist

Lookalife Music - NY, NY USA || Sydney, NSW

6/2004-Present

- Strong understanding of industry standard technologies including MIDI, ProTools, Logic X and Analog to Digital audio conversion.
- Coordinated and managed teams of 3 to 8 members to maximize creative output and foster vibrant and positive group dynamic.
- Leveraged emerging software and hardware technology to ensure leading edge performance outcomes.
- Maintained and repaired vintage electronic systems to ensure industry standard performance expectations were met.
- Collaborations with Track Tribe Music to compose, produce and perform content for pre-cleared audio libraries, utilized by Google and YouTube.

Bassist/Consultant

Broadway Productions (Multiple) - NY, NY

3/2016-5/2023

- Bassist for Broadway productions Paramour and Mean Girls.
- Managed medium sized teams, handling quality control, scheduling and assuring stakeholder satisfaction of product.
- Consulting services to Touring Company outlining technical and musical expectations to ensure seamless onboarding of personnel.
- As Associate Contractor was responsible for light payroll duties and high pressure management of staffing situations.

Bassist/Synthesist

Big Data - Brooklyn, NY USA

7/2014-8/2017

- Extensive touring and recording in support of hit single "Dangerous" (Warner Brothers).
- Skills navigating high pressure scenarios as a team, fostering a positive and productive dynamic.
- Assistance with logistics and personnel management while on remote locations.